SANJAY SUBBARAO

Immigrant Startup Enthusiast | UW I-Corp NSF Startup Mentor

@ sanjay.subbarao@outlook.com codinggambit.github.io/my_polite_inquiries/

J 408-685-8350

Seattle Metropolitan Area @sanjaysrao88 in aiwhiz

Olympia,WA

EXPERIENCE

Senior Technical Program Manager

Zappos Inc

Feb 2022 - Present

Olympia, WA

• Search Analytics: Generate Insights into Customer Behavior and feedback from CTRs, Search Depth, Product Pages, Unique search terms and Optimization based on them.

Senior Wireless & SDK Engineer

NXP Semiconductor

Dec 2019 - Feb 2022

San Jose, CA

- Connectivity Feasibility Analysis: Synthesize user requirements and technical constraints into a comprehensive design and actionable estimates for production time, costs, and viability.
- Requirements Definition: Define Qualification Requirements for customizable solutions for Bluetooth based on Profile level support(A2DP, HFP, SCO) and Stack(Bluez, Bluedroid) related requirements

Senior Wireless Engineer

Marvell Semiconductor

Apr 2019 - Dec 2019

- Santa Clara, CA
- Collaborative Design: Interfaced with multiple teams and sought out metrics for improvement. Streamlined functionality based testing and validation which reduced testing time by about 15 percent
- Process Optimization Reviewed processes to avoid redundancies and created a positive feedback loop to reduce turnaround time by around 10 percent.

Wireless Engineer II

Marvell Semiconductor

Apr 2017 - Apr 2019

- Santa Clara, CA
- Driver Integration: Performed Partner Platform bring up activities involving driver porting, platform validation and code check in into partner code repositories.
- Feature Validation: Developed sample applications for Wireless Proprietary features and validated it on Partner designs and documented it.

Wireless Engineer

Marvell Semiconductor

Feb 2015 - Apr 2017

- Santa Clara, CA
- Partner Interaction: Involved in Issue debugging, log capture, analysis and communication of Issue Resolution description interfacing Partner
- Demo Bring up: Bringing up demos to showcase various features such as Wireless Casting, Time Sync, Angle of Arrival and description for trade shows such as Consumer Exhibition Showcase

SUMMARY

MBA-Educated Technology leader with over 10+ years of experience in AI, ML and IOT in consumer scale product development and integration launching over 300 Million products involving 8 Generations of Google Products. Worked on Software integration on a wide generation of utilities from bring up stages to Product shipment.

STRENGTHS

Partner Management

Engaging with partners to gather metrics, track and ensure focus on goal oriented problem solving



Product Engineering

Feature Development, Problem Definition, Solution Brainstorming and envisioning easier methods of user interaction



Product Definition and Growth

Defining Search KPIs and potential impacts of feature launches via A/B Testing and Data Visualization

SKILLS

Data Visualization

Feature Development

Cross-functional Teamwork & Coordination

Data Analytics

Feature Documentation

Team Leadership

Product Spec Definition

KPI Metrics

PROGRAMMING

Python

C C++

Bash Tableau



PUBLICATIONS

Thesis

• Subbarao, Sanjay (2015). An 8-PSK super regenerative receiver: Design and simulation. California State University, Long Beach.

Journal Articles

• Tower, John et al. (2019). "Behavioral and molecular markers of death in Drosophila melanogaster". In: *Experimental Gerontology* 126, p. 110707. ISSN: 0531-5565. DOI: https://doi.org/10.1016/j.exger.2019.110707. URL: https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0531556519303055.

Conference Proceedings

- Wagdy, M. F. et al. (2015). "An 8-PSK receiver using an integrated low-noise amplifier super-regenerative oscillator with digital detection technique". In: 2015 IEEE International Conference on Electronics, Circuits, and Systems (ICECS), pp. 416–420.
- Sanketh, K. P., S. Subbarao, and K. A. Jolapara (2010). "I2V and V2V communication based VANET to optimize fuel consumption at traffic signals". In: 13th International IEEE Conference on Intelligent Transportation Systems, pp. 1251–1255.

EDUCATION

Executive Master in Business Administration

Quantic School of Business and Technology

Mar 2021

Nanodegree in Business Analytics Udacity

Feb 2019

M.S. in Electrical Engineering California State University, Long Beach

Aug 2015

B.E. in Electronics and Communication

Visvesvaraya Technological University

H Jul 2010